Time waits for one man.
3:10 to Yuma is a western film directed by James Mangold.
In Arizona in the late 1800s, infamous outlaw Ben Wade and his vicious gang
of thieves and murderers have plagued the Southern Railroad.
When Wade is captured, Civil War veteran Dan Evans, struggling to survive on his drought-plagued ranch,
volunteers to deliver him alive to the "3:10 to Yuma", a train that will take the killer to trial.
Ben Wade, played by Russell Crowe.
Dan Evans, played by Christian Bale.
Byron McElroy, played by Peter Fonda.
Alice Evans, played by Gretchen Mol.
Charlie Prince, played by Ben Foster.
Grayson Butterfield, played by Dallas Roberts.
3:10 to Yuma is a 2007 American  Western action drama film directed by James Mangold and produced by Cathy Konrad, starring Russell Crowe and Christian Bale in
the lead roles, with supporting performances by Peter Fonda, Gretchen Mol, Ben Foster, Dallas Roberts, Alan Tudyk, Vinessa Shaw, and Logan Lerman.
Bale plays a rancher impoverished by drought who takes on the dangerous but
lucrative job of taking a notorious outlaw (Crowe) to justice.
It is the second adaptation of Elmore Leonard's 1953 short story
"Three-Ten to Yuma", after the 1957 film of the same name.
Filming took place in various locations in New Mexico.
3:10 to Yuma opened September 7, 2007, in the United States
and received positive reviews from critics.
It grossed $71 million worldwide on a budget of $48–55 million.
The film explores themes of dying and death, race against
time, hero, saloon, parent child relationship.